SAM TAYLOR

Profile

Developer with nine years of professional experience in building client mobile applications.

Skills

iOS application development Numerous published iOS apps and games developed both alone and as part of teams serving huge userbases. Objective-C	Scripting Professional experience setting up continuous integration and various developer utilities, with a solid understanding of Linux/OSX systems and the command line environment. XCode, Storyboards & AutoLayout	Architecture design Proven ability to design, test and develop complex network-driven applications against various different server technologies. OCMock
---	--	--

Technical

Objective-C	XCode, Storyboards & AutoLayout	OCMock
Scripting (Python, Bash, Lua)	CLI tools, Vim, regex	Git
Cocoapods	C.I. (TeamCity, Jenkins)	Java, J2ME
C++, 2D game dev	Web (HTML, CSS, Flask)	Parse, Protocol Buffers

Experience

Badoo Ltd.

Senior iOS Developer

2011-2015

Worked as part of a large and growing team to build the company's main product, *Badoo*, (which caters for over 200 million users across all platforms), as well as the apps *Hot or Not* and *Blendr*. As the team scaled up I moved into a small core team responsible for the iOS 'platform' library on top of which the feature team could develop new features rapidly. Setup and managed TeamCity agents and build configurations before handing over to a full-time release engineer. Developed the greenfield project *Bumble* (with the former co-founder and designers of *Tinder*) from the start as part of a smaller internal team.

weComm Ltd. / OpenText Corporation

Senior iOS Developer

2009-2011

Responsible for developing client-side iPhone and iPad applications, with flexible, dynamic GUI construction; either using, customising or reimplementing almost all native components. Worked as part of a team of three to extend and maintain a core client upon which the App Store releases were produced. These include: NBA Gametime team apps, Turner Classic Movies, HotelScene, SportsBoost, and MiniVTV. Refactored the client architecture heavily throughout my employment to dramatically improve readability and code quality as well as optimising performance and memory usage. Set up a Continuous Integration server using Jenkins and was responsible for maintaining the build machine (based on Java / Ant).

Cobra Mobile Ltd.

Mobile Developer

2006-2009

Worked as the sole programmer (working closely with an artist) on the following titles: Powerpuff Girls: Mojo Madness (J2ME), Dastardly & Muttley in Their Flying Machines (J2ME), Beat the Intro (J2ME), Numba (J2ME), Mouse About & Mouse About Lite (iOS), Nose About (official Comic Relief game 2009) (iOS), and Stuck (iOS). Ported the J2ME games to approximately 70 handsets in multiple languages, as well as porting inherited projects such as Family Guy and Mind Games. Worked as part of a small team on Lego Batman for the iPhone, writing two of the mini-games: Fear in the Sky and Penguin Pinball. Developed numerous prototypes including an isometric demo in J2ME. The job involved overcoming severe device limitations and maintaining and refactoring the game engine.

Education

University of Abertay Dundee

2002-2006

BSc Computing (Mobile Game Development) with Second Class Honours (1st Division)

Hobbies

DJ'ing, attempting to learn French, badminton, snowboarding, skating, poker, juggling, camping, and learning new programming frameworks, currently with a strong interest in Clojure and genetic programming. I have developed a few software products in my spare time which can be found on darkfunction.com, my tech blog, and on my GitHub profile.

References

Available on request.